manilla.com 2011-05-03

# Manilla » Privacy Policy

**Manilla** **Privacy Policy**

Version 1.5

_(effective as February 26, 2011)_

At Manilla, our most important asset is our relationship with you.  Manilla (“Manilla” or “we” or “us”) is committed to maintaining the confidentiality, integrity, and security of personally identifiable information about our current and prospective users.  We take the utmost care in protecting your privacy when you visit Manilla.com (the “Site”) or use the service we provide (the “Service”).  This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, and disclose information that we collect about you through the Service and how we protect the security of your personally identifiable information.  We regularly re-evaluate our privacy and security policies and adapt them as necessary to address new developments and new challenges.

1.                      We limit the information we collect.

Information will be collected directly by Manilla or by third party services providers with whom we contract to act on our behalf.  We require any third party services provider to hold your information securely and in confidence and to use it only to fulfill the function(s) they have been retained to perform. ****

Manilla collects the following categories of information about you                through                      the Service:

  * Information That You Enter.  We will collect any personally identifiable information that you provide when you register for Manilla and that you choose to enter through the Service (including in comments or other content that you submit to us).  This will include personally identifiable information such as your name, email address, and zip code.

**** For third party websites that you wish to access and manage through our Service (your “Accounts”), we also will collect the passwords and user names that you provide to us.  We will only use this information in order to access those third party websites on your behalf for purposes of providing the Service.

We will ask you for information when you register, or at other times, such as if you choose to post to our blogs or respond to surveys that we may offer.  Please note that any personally identifiable information you voluntarily submit on a blog or other public areas we will from time to time offer on the Site can be viewed and used by other users, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  Manilla is not responsible for your disclosure of information in these forums.

  * Information from Third Party Web Sites.  In order to display financial information to you within the Service, we collect, on your behalf, and aggregate (for your viewing only) account information, documents, and other personally identifiable information from Accounts that you register on the Service
  * Automated Access Information.  Through a variety of methods that are widely used on the Internet, we also will automatically collect information about your computer or mobile device when you access and use the Site.  For example, when you visit Manilla.com, we may collect your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, which is a number automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet Services Provider whenever you use the Internet.  We also may collect and retain information about the pages you visit on the Manilla.com website; the website or search engine, if any, that referred you to Manilla.com; the website you visit after Manilla.com; other information about the type of web browser, computer, platform, related software and settings you are using; any search terms you have entered on this website or a referral site; other web usage activity and data logged by our web servers; and information relating to advertising, such as the ads you see, and the ads you click on.  Similarly, if you use a mobile device to access the Services, we may collect information about that device, such as the type of mobile device you use, your mobile telephone number, or a device identifier, as well as the date, time, and content of your messages relevant to your use of our mobile services.  As the Internet evolves, we may also collect other types of information, consistent with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use.

We use this automated information for internal system administration, to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website.  Such information also may be used to gather broad demographic information, such as country of origin and Internet Service Provider.  We also may link this information with your personal information when we feel that it is necessary to enforce compliance with our rules and policies or Terms of Use or to protect our Site, customers, or others.

2.          We use your personally identifiable information for these purposes:

  * to provide the Service;
  * for internal system administration;
  * to help diagnose problems with our server;
  * to administer the Site and analyze Site usage on an anonymous basis;
  * to gather broad demographic information;
  * to enforce compliance with our rules and policies or Terms of Use;
  * to contact you to provide information about Manilla, the Service, or changes to this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Use;
  * to send you  offers from Manilla and your Account providers;
  * to respond to your requests, questions, and comments; and
  * to protect our rights and the rights of others, including to enforce our Terms of Use, to detect and protect against error, fraud, or other criminal activity, to respond to legal process and defend against legal claims, and as otherwise required by law, as determined by Manilla in its sole discretion;

3.    We do not sell your personally identifiable information.

We do not and will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to anyone, for any reason, at any time.  We may share your personally identifiable information only as follows:

  * with the providers of your Accounts in order to provide you with the Service;
  * with authorized vendors that help us provide the Service or perform other business functions for us, such as sending emails or hosting the Site (but these vendors are not permitted to use personally identifiable information that we provide for any purpose other than to provide services to us);
  * to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or another government agency; or to establish or exercise our legal rights; or to defend against legal claims;
  * when we believe it is necessary, in our sole discretion, to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities; or as otherwise required by law;
  * on an anonymized basis for valid business purposes;
  * to enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements; or otherwise protect or defend the rights or property of Manilla, its affiliates, or others; or the safety of the public; or

to a successor in interest to our business in the event of a divestiture, merger, consolidation, asset sale, change of control or transfer of our business.

4.    How we use cookies.

Manilla uses various technologies to store information on your computer and / or mobile device and to provide you with content, including cookies and web beacons.  Cookies are text files we place in your computer’s and / or mobile device’s browser.  These will be used to store your preferences, to personalize your experience at the Site, and to save your password.  If you want to use the Service, you must leave cookies enabled. The Service will not work without them. Web beacons are electronic files that allow us and our advertisers to count users or to access certain cookies to enable the delivery of information tailored to your interests.

5.    We protect the information we collect.

We take the privacy of your personal information very seriously. We use firewall barriers, SSL 128-bit encryption techniques and authentication procedures, and other technical measures to maintain the security of your online session and to protect Manilla accounts and systems from unauthorized access.  To learn more about our security practices see security@manilla.com.

We strive to use the highest commercially acceptable means to protect your personally identifiable information, but no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, can be 100% secure at all times.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personally identifiable information.  In the unlikely event that we believe that the security of your personally identifiable information in our possession or control may have been compromised, we will seek to notify you as promptly as possible in the circumstances, by email or other means where we deem in our discretion that such notification is appropriate.

Manilla also has designed a security program to protect the security of customer information, protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to the security of that information, and protect against unauthorized access to such information that could result in harm to our customers.  Under the Manilla security program, only Manilla employees whose job functions require access to customer information will have access to your personally identifiable information, and even in those cases they will only be authorized to use it for the purposes that are required to provide the Service and otherwise comply with our Terms of Use. All Manilla employees undergo financial and criminal background checks as a condition of employment. Your personal data and documents are encrypted and stored in a facility protected by 24 x 7 security and biometric controls. We don’t store your personal information in logs or other unsecured repositories, and we don’t search or extract data from your documents.

6.    Third-party advertisements and websites

Manilla will use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on the Site. In the course of serving advertisements, third-party cookies will be placed on or recognized by your browser through the use of web beacons or similar technologies.  These cookies enable us and our third-party ad serving companies to serve you ads that you may find of interest. You can visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "NAI Opt Out") at Manilla will use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on the Site. In the course of serving advertisements, third-party cookies will be placed on or recognized by your browser through the use of web beacons or similar technologies.  These cookies enable us and our third-party ad serving companies to serve you ads that you may find of interest. You can visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "NAI Opt Out") at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> to learn more about online behavioral advertising and to see your opt-out choices from NAI member companies.

The Site includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on the Service to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

The Site will contain links to and ads from, third-party websites, partners, and sponsors, whose privacy and information security practices will be different than ours. Manilla does not control the privacy practices of other websites or businesses to which we provide hyperlinks or access, and the information practices of such companies are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  Accordingly, if you choose to access any of these third-party websites or services, you should read the privacy notices and user disclosures on those other websites and evaluate their practices before deciding to disclose any information or use any services.

to learn more about online behavioral advertising and to see your opt-out choices from NAI member companies.

The Site will contain links to and ads from, third-party websites, partners, and sponsors, whose privacy and information security practices will be different than ours. Manilla does not control the privacy practices of other websites or businesses to which we provide hyperlinks or access, and the information practices of such companies are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  Accordingly, if you choose to access any of these third-party websites or services, you should read the privacy notices and user disclosures on those other websites and evaluate their practices before deciding to disclose any information or use any services.

7.    Commercial Email Messages/Ability to “opt-out.”

Registered users of the Service will be sent periodic commercial emails. If you no longer wish to receive emails from Manilla, please send an email to optout@Manilla.com. Please note that, even if you opt-out of receiving commercial emails from us, we may still contact you to provide you with non-commercial messages, such as Service-related emails or billing or legal notices.

8.    Children’s privacy.

Manilla’s Terms of Use require that a user be at least eighteen years of age or above.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of eighteen.  Should we learn that a child under the age of eighteen has provided us with personal information, we will delete that information from our database and terminate that account.

9.    Non-U.S. users.

Manilla is based in the United States and our offices are headquartered in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, the information you provide to us will be processed and transferred to the United States and be subject to U.S. law.  By using the Site, participating in the Service, or by providing us with your information, you consent to this collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the United States.

10\. Managing your Account

You have control of your personal information on the Site.  To edit or change your personal information, logon to the Site, go to the Profile tab, then select the Edit button, then select Edit Account from the pull down menu and make the appropriate changes.  You will be asked to confirm the changes.  If you change your email address confirming emails will be sent to both your old and new email addresses.  You must click the link back to the Site to finalize the email update. To cancel your account, logon to the Site, go to the Profile tab, then select the Edit button.  Select the Delete Account option from the pull down menu.  You will be asked to confirm your deletion; select yes. Your account will be deleted in 30 days following your confirmation of the deletion.

11\. Ownership of data; deletion of account.

Your data belongs to you, and you may cancel your account at anytime by following the procedures described above for cancelling an account.   If you ask us to delete your account, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to remove your documents and personally identifiable data (including data that allows us to access the Accounts that you previously set up on the Service) from our servers. Despite such removal, portions of your data may remain on our servers indefinitely. You will be responsible for notifying any Accounts that have ceased delivery of hard copy mail that you wish to receive documents from them by means other than the Service. Manilla shall not have any liability in the event that an Account fails to communicate with you via alternate means.

12\. Changes to this policy.

We reserve the right at our discretion to update this Privacy Policy in the future.  We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the email address you provided to us or by placing a notice on the home page of the Service.   Continued use of the Service after any update constitutes your agreement to the new Privacy Policy for any information collected after the update.

If you have you have any questions, concerns, or suggestions about this Privacy Policy, you may contact Manilla at: [privacy@Manilla.com](mailto:privacy@Manilla.com).

Manilla, LLC

300 W 57th Street, 15th Floor

New York, New York 10019
